jobs.net 2011-12-31

# 

* * *

Effective Date: September 15, 2010

CareerBuilder, LLC and its subsidiaries and divisions (collectively, “CareerBuilder”, “We” or “Our”) has drafted its Privacy Policy to ensure that you can use CareerBuilder’s sites on your own terms. CareerBuilder continues to strive to provide the safest possible environment for you to search for and apply to jobs.

## CareerBuilder Precautions

* * *

### Overview

We have created this Privacy Policy to inform you of our collection, use and disclosure practices regarding personal information that we collect through CareerBuilder websites. This Privacy Policy applies only to data gathered on any web site under CareerBuilder’s control (collectively, the “Sites”), and does not apply to any other information or web site. This Privacy Policy incorporates by reference the Terms and Conditions for the Sites, which apply to this privacy policy.

Please review this Privacy Policy periodically as we may update it from time to time. Each time you visit the Sites or provide us with information, you are, by doing so, accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy at that time. If we materially change our practices with regard to personal information collected under a prior privacy policy, we will endeavor to notify you and give you the opportunity to opt out of changes with regard to that previously collected information. You agree that by using the Sites you are expressly and affirmatively consenting to our use and disclosure of the information that you provide, and consenting to receive emails, as described below. 

### Personal Information

In order to operate the Sites in an efficient and effective manner and provide users with information on job postings and services that may be of interest to them, CareerBuilder may collect personal information, including contact information (such as an email address), from its users. In addition, this information allows us to provide users with private and secure areas to post and modify their original content on our Sites (e.g., jobs and resumes). We also automatically track certain information based upon your behavior on the Sites and use this information to do internal research on our users’ demographics, interests, and behavior to better understand, protect and serve users in general. This information may include the URL that a user has just come from (whether this URL is on our Sites or not), the URL a user goes to next (whether this URL is on our Sites or not), a user’s computer browser information, and their IP address. You agree that CareerBuilder may use your personal information to contact you and deliver information to you that, in some cases, is targeted to your interests (such as relevant job postings, services, educational or other career development opportunities), or provide administrative notices or communications applicable to your use of the Sites. By accepting this Privacy Policy, you expressly agree to receive this information. If you do not wish to receive these communications, we encourage you to opt out of any further receipt by following the opt out provisions provided in each such communication. CareerBuilder may also aggregate certain non-personally identifiable information about its users (such as occupation, location, education and experience) and use such anonymous information to prepare reports that it provides to its users.

We do not sell our users’ personally identifiable information to anyone for any reason if the user has indicated a desire for us to keep the information private. When posting jobs and resumes, our users decide for themselves how much contact information they wish to display (we enable private communication for those who choose to hide this information).

All users should be aware, however, that when they choose to display or distribute personal information (such as their email address or resume) via the Sites or any other distribution method, that information can be collected and used by others. This may result in unsolicited messages from third parties for which CareerBuilder is not responsible. Also, you may have arrived at the Sites by following a link from a CareerBuilder newspaper affiliate or other affiliate’s web site. If so, please be aware that CareerBuilder may share your information with that affiliate and the affiliate may use the information consistent with its privacy policy instead of this one.

CareerBuilder may also disclose specific user information when we determine that such disclosure is necessary to comply with the law, to cooperate with or seek assistance from law enforcement or to protect the interests or safety of CareerBuilder or other users of the Sites. In addition, personal information we have collected may be passed on to a third party in the event of a transfer of ownership or assets or a bankruptcy of CareerBuilder. Such disclosures may be made with or without your consent, and with or without notice.

### Credit Card Security

CareerBuilder employs encryption for secure credit card transactions.

### About Cookies and Third Party Advertisers

CareerBuilder uses cookies for the protection and convenience of our users. Cookies enable us to serve secure pages to our users without asking them to sign in repeatedly. If a user’s system is idle for more than an hour, however, the cookie will expire, forcing the user to sign in again to continue their session. This prevents unauthorized access to the user’s information while they are away from their computer. CareerBuilder may store non-personally identifying information about you such as past jobs viewed and job searches conducted by your computer in a cookie that it places on your computer. We do this in order to present you with job recommendations based on your interests as expressed previously through your searches. Most Internet browsers enable you to erase cookies from your computer hard drive, block all cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. To obtain instructions regarding deleting or disabling cookies, [click here](http://www.careerbuilder.com/Jobseeker/Page.aspx?pagever=remove-cookies). Please be aware; however, that some CareerBuilder features or services may not function properly without cookies.

Third-Party Advertisers: We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit the Sites. These companies may use information about your visits to these and other web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. We also may give third party advertisers the ability to tailor their advertisements on our Sites using demographic and preference information we provide to them in aggregate form. This information does not identify you individually.

These third party advertising companies may use this information to provide you with advertising on our Sites, other websites, or other service platforms or devices tailored to the interests indicated by your browsing our of Sites and/or your interaction with other web sites where these ad servers or networks are also present. 

The third party advertising companies who deliver ads for CareerBuilder on the Sites may place or access cookies on your computer hard drive to distinguish your web browser uniquely and to keep track of information relating to serving ads on your web browser, such as the type of ads shown and the webs pages on which the ads appeared. The third party advertising companies may use cookies to keep track of the web sites that your web browser visits across the advertising provider’s network of web sites with whom it works. These companies may combine this information with other information they have collected relating to your web browser’s activities across their network of web sites. 

These companies operate under their own privacy policies and CareerBuilder encourages you to be aware of the privacy policies of such companies before you choose to allow them to place a cookie on your web browser. CareerBuilder does not have control over or access to any information contained in the cookies that are set on your computer by third party advertisers. To prohibit the automatic collection of information by some of the third party advertisers, you may opt out at the [Network Advertising Initiative opt out site](http://networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). Please note that this opt out is cookie-based. If you buy a new computer, change web browsers or delete this cookie, you will need to perform the opt-out task again. To obtain instructions regarding deleting or disabling cookies from third party advertising companies that are not members of the National Advertising Initiative, please [click here](http://www.careerbuilder.com/Jobseeker/Page.aspx?pagever=remove-cookies).

In addition, some of the employers that use our Sites may place cookies on your computer through their job postings and may use such cookies to distinguish your web browser uniquely. Often, employers use such information to track the effectiveness of their job postings by measuring how many users who view their postings later became job applicants. To obtain instructions regarding deleting or disabling cookies, please [click here](http://www.careerbuilder.com/Jobseeker/Page.aspx?pagever=remove-cookies).

### Safe Harbor

CareerBuilder has certified its adherence to the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Safe Harbor Principles in connection with the U.S. implementation of the European Union Data Protection Directive. For more information about the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles and to view the certification for CareerBuilder, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Safe Harbor web site. You may also contact us directly at **(866) 438-1485** to learn more about this certification. In addition, CareerBuilder is a member of the BBBOnLine U.S./E.U. Safe Harbor Dispute Resolution program. Please consult the BBBOnLine website at [www.bbbonline.org](http://www.bbbonline.org/) for more information concerning the BBBOnLine privacy programs and dispute resolution procedures.

### What You Should Know

CareerBuilder cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personal information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. Therefore, although we are committed to protecting your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information or private communications will always remain private. As a user of the Sites, you understand and agree that you assume all responsibility and risk for your use of the Sites, the internet generally, and the documents you post or access and for your conduct on and off the Sites.

### Your California Privacy Rights

California law permits its residents to request and receive information about a business’ disclosure of certain categories of personal information to other companies for their use in direct marketing. If you are a California resident and a user of any of the Sites, you can request a copy of this information from CareerBuilder by sending an email to [customer.service@careerbuilder.com](mailto:customer.service@careerbuilder.com) or a letter to CareerBuilder at 5550-A Peachtree Parkway, Norcross, Georgia 30092, Attention: Customer Service. Please include your name and email address in email requests, and your name and postal address in mail requests.

## Protect Yourself

* * *

### Some Important Tips To Use When Dealing With Prospective Employers

  * Never give out your social security number to a prospective employer. 
  * Never provide credit card or bank numbers or engage in a monetary transaction of any sort. 
  * Be cautious when dealing with contacts outside of your own country.
  * Do not provide any non-work related personal information (i.e. social security number, eye color, marital status, etc.) over the phone or online.

### Other Privacy Features On the Sites

You never need to provide personally identifiable data to search for jobs on our Sites. Logging into the Sites is always optional for you, (although logging in does give you access to smarter job search tools such as my careerbuilder, Personal Search Agents and Saved Searches.) 

### Post a Resume

Posting your resume on the Sites puts you in front of thousands of employers with open positions each day. When you post your resume, we automatically create a registration for you using the email address and password that you supply. When you return to the Sites in the future you will use that same email address and password to access and edit your existing resume.

### Resume Privacy Options

We know that our job seekers have varying levels of comfort when it comes to posting their resume on the Internet. To accommodate the needs of all users, CareerBuilder has 3 levels of privacy from which you can choose. Please note that these privacy settings only apply to whether or not or to what extent your resume can be view by third parties. CareerBuilder will still collect, use or disclose anonymous, aggregated information about you and your visits to our website in the manner described above.

### 1\. Standard Posting

    This option gives you the most visibility to the broadest employer audience possible by making your resume searchable in our Resume Database. If you select this option, any registered employer user can view your resume and contact details. Potential employers may also use our “Applicant Explorer” feature which provides employers which search engine results generated by searching your name and various details from your resume.

### 2\. Anonymous Posting

    You can also post to the public resume database without any of your contact information being displayed. (If you use this option be sure to remove your contact information from the body of the resume.) The anonymous option also allows you to display only selected pieces of contact information.

### 3\. Private Posting For Apply Online Only

    This option allows you to post your resume on the Sites without having it searched by employers. The benefit is that you can quickly and easily apply for jobs without retyping your information.

### Your General Contact Information

Managing your privacy is as simple as selecting which pieces of your contact information are displayed. This is done in the section of the resume form called “Contact Information.” Using option 3 above requires that you select the Apply Online Only option from the “Contact Information” section at the bottom of the edit form, as shown below.

### Microsoft Windows Live? ID

In addition to the CareerBuilder sign-in, CareerBuilder offers the ability to sign in using Microsoft Windows Live ID service, which provides authentication for online sign in. When you sign in to this site using the Windows Live ID service you will be asked to provide your e-mail address and a password to sign you in. This same Windows Live ID sign-in allows you to access many other participating Windows Live ID web sites.

## How To Spot Fraud

* * *

### Email and Online Fraud – Phishing

Unfortunately, email and online fraud are continuing concerns for virtually all businesses that operate on the Internet. Please be aware that, from time to time, fraudulent emails have been circulated to CareerBuilder users that appear to be from CareerBuilder but which are, in fact, sent by fraudsters trying to steal your login credentials. CareerBuilder is not sending these fraudulent emails. If you receive an email or pop-up window requesting that you sign in to CareerBuilder and provide your personal information, check the link by hovering your mouse over it. If the link appears different than the link printed in the email, **_do not respond_**. If you are in doubt, please contact [TSST@CareerBuilder.com](mailto:TSST@careerbuilder.com).

Below is an example of one such fraudulent email:

### False Jobs and Scams:

Occasionally, you may also receive email that look like CareerBuilder Job offers. These email messages typically spoof the CareerBuilder logo, disclaimer, and other information. Such email messages do NOT come from CareerBuilder, but from scammers attempting to scam you out of money or confidential information. Be especially cognizant of the salary offered and the time required to perform the duties. If it looks too good to be true, it probably is! An example is provided below:

### Help Us Monitor Fraud

Please be advised that CareerBuilder will not request that you log in, download software, or provide personal information. If you ever receive a request for this type of sensitive information, please do not respond and immediately contact CareerBuilder customer service at **(866) 438-1485** or report the suspected fraud to [TSST@careerbuilder.com](mailto:TSST@careerbuilder.com).

If you think you have been a victim of fraud, immediately report the situation to your local police and contact us at [TSST@careerbuilder.com](mailto:TSST@careerbuilder.com).

Helpful Links For Fraud Security:

### How to Contact Us

You can direct questions regarding this Privacy Policy to CareerBuilder by emailing us at [customer.service@careerbuilder.com](mailto:customer.service@careerbuilder.com) or by letter to CareerBuilder at 5550-A Peachtree Parkway, Norcross, Georgia 30092, Attention: Customer Service. Please include your name and email address in email requests, and your name and postal address in mail requests.
